Achref Nejah

Full Stack Web Developer | Python | Django | React | JAVA Spring Boot

≤ achref.nejah@gmail.com

(+216) 92 412 267

В

in Achref Nejah

NejahA

Professional Portfolio

PROFILE

I'm a Full Stack Web Developer with a civil engineering background, specializing in Python, Django, React, and Java Spring Boot. I've built web applications, including tourist and e-commerce platforms. My strong problem-solving skills and passion for web development drive me to seek challenging opportunities in the tech industry.

PROJECTS

Tunist

Full Stack Developer | Team `| 4 Weeks

I developed a web Application that aims to link upcoming tourists in Tunisia with local guides, offering a unique and safe experience with the possibility of learning more about their destination through Blogs and renting a suitable accommodation.

- Implementation of Java and Spring Boot for developing the backend.
- · Working on the backend and debugging server related errors through research and outsourcing.
- Implementation of a responsive map interface in the web application using Leaflet.
- Developing both the front-end and back-end the admin dashboard using React and Java.

Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, React, Leaflet, MySQL, VS Code, Balsamiq.

Rewear

FullStack Developer & Scrum Master | Team | 2 Weeks

I developed an an e-commerce platform where the users of the web app can buy or sell articles of clothing fostering recycling for second-hand garments.

- Working on the back-end controller and routes using Express JS.
- Implementing & debugging the "upload images" feature in the application using Multer.
- Implementing & debugging the "instant messaging" feature in the application using Socket.io.
- Working on parsing data to React's components.

Technologies: React, Coolors, Mongoose, Express JS, Mongo DB, Multer, Socket.io, Node JS, VS Code, Balsamiq.

Fodhni

FullStack Developer & Scrum Master | Team | 2 Weeks

I developed a platform that connects service providers to clients and delivers quality services to the persons who need them.

- Applying Django for both the front-end and the back of the web application through working on the backend controller.
- Creating the database using Postgres.
- Working on view templates using Django.

Technologies: Django, Postgres, Jinja, Python, VS Code, Balsamiq, Coolors

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sales Representative

05/2023 - 07/2023

Tregi

- Conducted cold Calling clients to promote products related to food and merchandise.
- Ensured closing sales and achieved the set objectives and key performance indicators.

Technical Assistant 09/2022 - 12/2022

Teleperformance

- Answered clients' requests and assistance via phone calls.
- Handled challenging complaints and escalated the complaints to ensure the resolution of the problem when needed while providing possible solutions.
- Coordinated with colleagues abroad regarding the process and implemented strategic guidelines to ensure a smoother workflow.

Customer Care Agent 05/2022 - 08/2022

Active Contact

- Assisted clients in navigating requests related to their mobiles by receiving phone calls or reaching out to clients directly.
- Solved issues efficiently and handled technical complaints while maintaining a strong sense of communication with the clients and colleagues.
- Matched and oriented the clients according to their needs to the contract best suited for them and provided continuous support in the matter.

EDUCATION

Diploma in Civil Engineering
ESPRIT

Baccalaureate in Mathematics
Beb El Khadhra Secondary School

09/2014 - 12/2021

09/2013 - 06/2014

CERTIFICATES

American Certification in Full Stack Web Development ℰ

Coding Dojo 2024

- •1200+ hours of coding in
- JavaScript, Python, and Java including 3 projects.
- •Pair Programming and work on algorithms daily.
- •Soft Skills training to enhance communication and team collaboration.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend:

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, React

Back End:

Python, Express JS, Node JS, Spring Boot, Postgres, Mongoose, MySQL

Frameworks:

Flask, Django, React

Tools

VS Code, Balsamiq, Postman, Coolors

HARD SKILLS

MS Office	Canva
Autocad	Git
Github	Trello

SOFT SKILLS

Time Management	Adaptabilty
Critical Thinking	Dynamism

LANGUAGES

English	French
EUZUSU	rrench

Professional Proficiency Professional Proficiency

Arabic

Native Proficiency

INTERESTS

Guitar | Retro Gaming